Jennifer Kiesler

Sun Prairie, WI

Phone: (262) 994-8243 | Email: kiesler.jen@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/JenniferKiesler

Portfolio: https://jenniferkiesler.github.io/kiesler-react-portfolio/LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jennifer-kiesler-aa469591/

Summary

A Software Developer with great problem solving skills. Has developed applications independently and as part of a group. Has acquired many transferable skills from previous work experiences including communication, collaboration, ability to adapt to change, and time management.

Technical Skills

GitHub, Git, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, REST APIs, Agile, Node.js, Jest, Express.js, MySQL, Postman, Heroku, Sequelize, MVC, Handlebars, NoSQL, PWA, React, GraphQL, MERN

Projects

House Rules | https://github.com/jonpfluger/house-rules.git | https://house-rules.herokuapp.com/

- Full Stack application | Group project (5)
- This application lets a user read posts about different types of games and write their own posts.
- JavaScript, Express.js, Sequelize, Handlebars, Bootstrap, MVC, Anime.js, Cloudinary

Toss Me A Book | https://github.com/JenniferKiesler/toss-me-a-book.git |

https://jenniferkiesler.github.io/toss-me-a-book/

- Front End application | Group project (4) | Project Manager and Lead Engineer
- This application helps the user find a book in many different ways including subject, title, author, or just have the application pick a book from the NYT best seller list that comes with a short description of the book
- HTML, CSS, Bulma, JavaScript, OpenLibrary API, Books API

Anywhere Forecast | https://github.com/JenniferKiesler/anywhere-forecast.git |

https://jenniferkiesler.github.io/anywhere-forecast/

- Front End application
- This application is for someone wanting to see the weather or weather outlook for specific cities.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, OpenWeather API

Neural Network API | https://github.com/JenniferKiesler/neural-network-api.git |

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1MRbFTvgvY1qxZLNrZG5JBLmUYCGX7dZG/view

- Back End NoSQL Database
- An API for a social network web application where users can share their thoughts, react to friends' thoughts, and create a friend list.
- Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose

Education

University of Wisconsin Coding Bootcamp (Madison, WI)	Expected February 2023
Currently enrolled	
Certificate in Full Stack Web Development	
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee (Milwaukee, WI)	May 2018
Biology and Chemistry Teaching Certifications	
University of Wisconsin-La Crosse (La Crosse, WI)	May 2014

Bachelor of Science (BS), Biology Major, Cellular/Molecular Emphasis, Chemistry Minor

Professional Experience

Science Teacher, Marshall High School (Marshall, WI)

August 2020-June 2021

- Taught 90 students in the allotted time frame by planning ahead and being adaptable which allowed for more successful lessons
- Differentiated lessons by determining which methods would work best for each class/individual student which allowed for more students to be successful in the classroom
- Communicated with parents by email or phone to ensure all students were successful and parents were up to date on the student's progress
- Adapted to teaching remote and in-class students at the same time by creating more virtual activities for all students to do which allowed for all students to be able to learn

Science Teacher, Denmark High School (Denmark, WI)

August 2019-May 2020

- Created a new biology curriculum by collaborating with co-workers to meet the new standards students should learn to be successful outside of high school
- Instructed and presented information in a clear, concise way by using multiple different methods including visual and audio to increase student learning
- Adjusted successfully to teaching remotely by modifying lessons to work for virtual learning which allowed students to learn effectively outside of the classroom

Science Teacher, MC² High School (Milwaukee, WI)

August 2018-June 2019

- Developed the science department curriculum by organizing activities and units into a flowchart to make sure the different curriculums taught the students the standards required for that subject
- Ability to work under pressure by creating lesson plans for the week and to do lists which allowed everything to get done on time
- Analyzed the lessons by looking at the data and reflecting on how successful the lessons and activities
 were to determine whether the lesson worked or if the lesson needed to be adjusted and retaught